Maxim Kashchenko

Software engineer

mkaschenko.me mkaschenko@me.com

PROFILE

I develop software for more than 10 years, mostly web applications. I solved problems in different domains, led teams, mentored colleagues, was part of product and outsourcing teams, worked remotely and onsite.

I can help you to collect requirements, transfer knowledge, onboard new members, lay the foundation for a new app, design and implement key functionality or refactor the hairy one.

I'm familiar with agile methodologies, continues delivery, test and behaviour driven development, also like pair programming.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Primary: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL.

• Secondary: Clojure, TypeScript, React.

EXPERIENCE

Software engineer / Team lead, Lockstep Labs, Bangkok, Feb 2016 – Feb 2019

Domains: e-commerce, visual analytics for retail banks, personal insurance in USA, enterprise learning.

Languages: Ruby, Clojure, SQL, TypeScript.

Others: Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, React, Redux, Amazon web Services, Git.

Participated in development of different products, designed and implemented key functionality, led teams, on-boarded new team members, collected feedback from colleagues.

Software engineer, <u>Hipflat</u>, Bangkok, Aug 2014 – Oct 2015

Domains: real estate, crawling and parsing.

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript.

Others: Rails, MongoDB, Redis, Algolia, Git.

Participated in development of the product, designed and implemented key functionality, attended to architecture and performance of the backend system.

Ruby on Rails developer / Team lead, <u>Arhont Information Security</u>, London (remote), Mar 2012 – Aug 2014

Domains: virtual data rooms, parsing.

Languages: Ruby, SQL.

Others: Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, Git.

Participated in development of the product, designed and implemented key functionality, attended to architecture and performance of the backend system, led the team, introduced and applied agile methodologies.

Ruby on Rails developer, Tulp.ru, Omsk, Mar 2010 – Oct 2011

Domains: review sites.

Languages: Ruby, SQL, JavaScript.

Others: Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, jQuery, Git.

Participated in development of the product, worked on both backend and frontend systems.

Ruby on Rails developer, Jazzcloud, Omsk, Sep 2009 – Mar 2010

Domains: e-commerce.

Languages: Ruby, SQL, JavaScript.

Others: Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, ¡Query, Amazon Web Services, Git.

Participated in development of different products, worked on both backend and frontend systems.

Ruby on Rails developer, Development Mill, Omsk, Jun 2007 – Aug 2009

Domains: crawling and parsing, content management systems.

Languages: Ruby, SQL, Javascript.

Others: Rails, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Git, SVN.

Participated in development of different products, worked on both backend and frontend systems.

EDUCATION

- M.Sc. in Databases (half-done), Omsk State Technical University, 2010 2011
- B.Sc. in Informatics and Computer Science, <u>Omsk State Technical University</u>, 2006 2010

READINGS

- Test Driven Development Kent Beck
- Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code Martin Fowler, Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, Don Roberts
- On the criteria to be used in decomposing systems into modules D. L. Parnas
- Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs Harold Abelson, Gerald Jay Sussman, Julie Sussman
- Quantum Psychology: How Brain Software Programs You and Your World Robert Anton Wilson

TOOLS

- Favorite editor Emacs
- First computer NES